<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Biblio99: Philosophy Streams</title>
    <link>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Biblio99: Philosophy Streams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Biblio99</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>John Stuart Mill on Free Speech</title>
      <link>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/jsmfreespeech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/jsmfreespeech/</guid>
      <description>On the next stream we&amp;rsquo;re taking a look at John Stuart Mill&amp;rsquo;s arguments for freedom of speech in chapter 2 of On Liberty: On the Liberty of Thought and Discussion. In particular, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at the idea of the marketplace of ideas.
We&amp;rsquo;re going to cover three different interpretations of Mill&amp;rsquo;s arguments:
  Absolutist: Any interference with an agent&amp;rsquo;s freedom of speech (properly understood) counts as a violation of liberty rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Echo Chambers with Epoch Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/epochconvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/epochconvo/</guid>
      <description>Our next stream is a conversation with Epoch Philosophy. He makes excellent videos on political theory and philosophy.
We&amp;rsquo;re talking about open-mindedness, echo chambers, and online discourse.
Join the discussion!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Austin&#39;s Command Theory of Law and Legal Positivsm</title>
      <link>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/austin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/austin/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Question  What are the validity conditions for a law? Under what conditions do laws exist?
 Legal Positivism  The existence laws depends on social facts and not on the merits of its content.  Austin&amp;rsquo;s Take  The existence of law is one thing its merit and demerit another. Whether it be or be not is one inquiry; whether it be or be not comfortable to an assumed standard is a different inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hart Dworkin Debate (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/hd2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/hd2/</guid>
      <description>The Question for Today  What is the relationship between law and morality?
  Hart&amp;rsquo;s Positivism  Model of Rules Primary and Secondary Rules The Seperability Thesis The Discretion Thesis   Dworkin&amp;rsquo;s Critiques of Hart  Sometimes judges are bound by moral principles in hard cases If that&amp;rsquo;s the case then the law in in part constituted by moral principles.   Positivist Responses to Dworkin  Exclusive Legal Positivists Inclusive Legal Positivism   Exclusive Legal Positivism  Dworkin&amp;rsquo;s principles have a social pedigree (like law), or These principles are just not law   Principles With Social Pedigree  Maybe Dworkin&amp;rsquo;s principles have a social pedigree?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hart Dworkin Debate (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/hd1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/hd1/</guid>
      <description>The Question for Today  What is the relationship between law and morality?
  A (Very) Short History of Legal Positivsm  Legal positivism is the thesis that the existence and content of law depends on social facts and not on its merits (Green and Adams, 2019).   Austinian Legal Positivism   John Austin (1790-1859) argued that laws are the commands of a sovereign backed by threat of sanctions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Law Theories</title>
      <link>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/naturallaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 19:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Marakelian.github.io/posts/naturallaw/</guid>
      <description>The Two Main Questions Q: What would a full understanding of the law include?
Q: Would a full understanding include some standard of rationality or only include some set of social facts?
The Two Main Principles of Law   Law is necessarily a socially recognized standard of conduct
  Law is necessarily a rational standard of conduct.
  Reasons for Action  The motivation for thinking (2) is that we need to explain how the law can provide us with reasons for us to act  What is Natural Law Anyway?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
